A Guide to the Montgomery Film Society Records 1956-1972
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Montgomery Film Society Records 1956-1972
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Ms73-007
1 container; 0.5 cu. ft.
Records of society devoted to bringing foreign, art, and classic films to Blacksburg, Virginia. Includes correspondence, membership lists and administrative notes (including constitution), film advertisements and reviews, film rental agreements, programs, and financial records.
Donor
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Montgomery Film Society Records were donated to Newman Library in 1973.
Biographical/Historical Information
Judging by the organizational records, The Montgomery Film Society was apparently founded in 1956. Based in Blacksburg, Virginia, the non-profit society's purpose was to bring foreign, art and classic films (often accompanied by short subject matter) to Blacksburg. Due to distributor-imposed regulations, the society's size was limited to 100 (later 200) members and tickets were available only on a season ticket subscription basis. The society's annual season ran from October to April and featured seven films, screened in an auditorium on the Virginia Tech campus. The Montgomery Film Society apparently disbanded in 1972.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of records of the Montgomery Film Society, a Blacksburg, Virginia organization devoted to viewing foreign, art and classic films. The collection includes the society's correspondence- - most of it from film distributors regarding the booking of films for the society's programs. The collection also includes the society's membership and administrative records (including its constitution), program notes and recommendations, film advertisements and reviews, film rental agreements and invoices, announcements regarding the society's programs, and financial records.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by document type, then chronologically.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Montgomery Film Society (Blacksburg, Va.)
Subjects:
Blacksburg (Va.); Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; Montgomery County (Va.)
Contents List
- Correspondence
  - 1956-1958 (Box-folder 1-1)
  - 1959-1961 (Box-folder 1-2)
  - 1962-1968 (Box-folder 1-3)
  - 1969-1972, n.d. (Box-folder 1-4)
- Membership and administrative records 1959-1971, n.d. (Box-folder 1-5)
  (includes society's constitution)
- Membership book 1956-1972 (Box-folder 1-6)
- Program notes and recommendations 1956-1970, n.d. (Box-folder 1-7)
- Film advertisements and reviews 1956-1968 (Box-folder 1-8)
- Film rental agreements and invoices
  - 1957-1967 (Box-folder 1-9)
  - 1968-1972 (Box-folder 1-10)
- Program announcements 1956-1972 (Box-folder 1-11)
- Bank account records 1956-1972 (Box-folder 1-12)
- Financial notes and receipts 1956-1971, n.d. (Box-folder 1-13)